What if the difference between
being good or bad at a subject
isn't a matter of knowing the right answers,
but rather a matter of knowing
how to find the right answers?
When you're bad at a subject, it's hard to
find helpful sample questions in textbooks
or search for them online.
So what should you do in that situation?
A few months ago, I don't think I knew.
But now I think I do.
The answer is to rely on someone.
Admit your shortcomings
and ask someone to teach you.
Then learn their shortcomings and see if
you can teach them something in return.
Give and take.
I was familiar with the concept,
but I think I understand it better now.
Leaning on other people is a skill.
We can't read each other's minds,
so if you don't tell anyone what you want,
they're left in the dark.
It isn't fair to make them guess.
If you want to ask for something,
you should say so.
If we could learn to understand each other's
feelings and compromise more,
everyone would be happier.
That's what I believe now.
But I've been violating my own policy.
There's one person I need to cooperate
and share my honest feelings with...
Episode 12 "
and
"
but I still can't do it.
Thank you very much.
Why don't you put some of that in here?
Hmm? Okay, can you take this, then?
Thanks.
You've got enough to carry already.
You're a real gentleman.
I'm really not. My little sister's just
always on my case about that stuff.
You have a little sister?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
Sorry. What were you just saying?
I wasn't saying anything at all.
You weren't?
Um, so...
You don't need to force a conversation.
This is exactly why I'm worried
about you, Asamura-kun.
The way you looked when
you showed up yesterday...
You had this expression like you
were running from something.
It's a look that I'm very familiar
with, so it bothered me.
You were actually studying,
so you weren't there to hit on me...
which means you were
probably looking for sanctuary.
Would you mind if I ordered some pudding?
Huh?
The pudding here is crazy good.
Do your problems have
something to do with love?
Why do you ask?
It all makes sense if you came
seeking refuge with another girl.
As if searching for a new love
to escape a painful experience.
The problem is... I fell for someone
that I never should've fallen for.
And if I got what I want now, it would
cause problems for everyone I know.
I know I need to forget the whole thing.
But I don't think I can.
That sounds serious.
Do you have time after cram school?
Let's hit the town tonight.
I want you to come out with me.
Um...
I really like you, Ayase.
I'm flattered.
I'm glad... that you told me...
But I'm sorry.
I don't think I'll ever be
able to see you that way.
Are you going out with someone?
No, I'm not.
Do you have a crush on anyone?
No, I... don't.
But it still wouldn't work?
It still wouldn't work.
Sorry. I won't bother you about it again.
See you later.
If you connect with another
person you're attracted to
and your feelings remain unchanged,
Sorry, Ayase-san.
I have to go somewhere, so I'll be home late.
then those are your true feelings,
and you should always treasure them.
Don't all those people look lost?
Huh?
When I walk around the city, I feel like
everyone in the world is living a mistake.
But I think that's the only way
some people know how to live.
I was one of them. In middle school,
I was among all these useless people.
Why are you telling me this?
Because you remind me of
my old self, and it pisses me off.
You were raised without anyone...
I mean, without any women
you could count on, right?
You're able to face things objectively.
That's a real gift.
But if I had to guess how you developed that,
I'd say it's because you grew up
without a woman to depend on.
Was it the same for you, Fujinami-san?
Yes.
But I lost my faith in humanity as a whole.
I lost both of my parents in an accident
when I was in middle school.
I found out that both of their families
had opposed their marriage.
Everyone mocked them at the funeral,
saying they got what they asked for.
The emotion that came over me at
the time wasn't hatred or sadness...
but a sense of resignation. Of giving up.
Ah, what a shame.
Tonight's the harvest moon, you know.
You say you have no faith in women,
but I think that's a lie.
Until my auntie set me straight,
I was so sure of the way I felt, too.
Your auntie?
We're family now.
She was worried about me staying out
all night and had the heart to adopt me.
She told me something
the day I moved in with her.
"You should try a little harder to make
peace with your heart," she said.
To reconcile, or maybe more like compromise...
She said, "Don't ignore your feelings."
"You think you've given up," she said.
"But are you sure you have?"
"I think you really did have faith in people,
but you feel that faith was betrayed."
"It must have been so painful for you."
Daddy...
When I heard that...
Mommy!
I guess I, well...
I think I spent the whole night crying.
Asamura-kun...
Do you think you might be trying to
bottle up and suffocate your feelings, too?
The feelings I have...
I can't let out.
Well, that would be fine
if suppressing them would make
them disappear one day.
But being objective and expecting nothing
from people are two different things.
I mean, we're all human.
We can't help having expectations.
Deceive your heart all you want, but if
you don't resolve this, it will scorn you.
And before you know it,
you'll be scarred forever.
But I can't be that selfish...
Yes, you can. Feelings are selfish things.
Monday, September 28th
You know, I think I saw you
yesterday, Ayase-san.
Huh?
Near my cram school.
Were you shopping at the store there?
Yeah.
I was at the restaurant across the street.
I think... you were with a guy who
looked like a classmate or something.
That was Shinjo-kun.
Oh. I couldn't tell.
Now can I ask you something?
Of course.
You were out late last night.
Where were you, Big Brother?
I was walking around Shibuya.
Just walking? Uh... with Yomiuri-san?
No, someone else.
Remember when I said I was going
to lunch with someone?
That was—
Wait.
Are we talking about a girl here?
Um, yeah.
Oh, okay. And?
Ah, right.
It gave me a chance to think about things.
So I want to work something out.
Work what out?
Listen, Ayase-san...
I think I have very strong feelings for you.
Liar.
I'm not lying.
Are you joking?
Do you think I'd make such a cruel joke?
No, you're right. You're right.
You'd never do something
so heartless, Asamura-kun.
Did you just call me Asamura?
Huh? Oh...
You said you have strong feelings?
Like, I really like you.
You mean as my brother?
Or as in... you want to touch
me and hold me and stuff?
Like, you get jealous when you see me
with other boys? Those kinds of feelings?
Yeah.
But siblings can feel that way, too, can't they?
Huh?
I mean, of course they can.
Hold on...
I heard that when someone's starved
for attention from the opposite sex
and suddenly gets a lot of time with them,
it's easy to develop feelings they could
confuse with romantic attraction.
That's just one possibility, right?
We can't rule it out.
Yeah, well...
Maybe just you have stronger than
normal feelings for me as your sister.
Could that explain it?
Ayase-san...
Sorry.
I'm okay with it.
Does this help?
Thank you for having the courage to tell me.
If you'd kept that bottled up,
it would've been so hard.
It really would have weighed on you.
But don't worry.
I think I can help you carry that weight, too.
Whether you have feelings for me
as my brother or something more,
I'm okay with it.
Whichever it is, I'm happy.
Okay.
I'm not sure myself
if the feelings I have for you are because
you're my brother or... something else.
But if I can give you some comfort by
hugging you, I truly want to do that.
And if you could hug me when I need it,
it'd truly make me happy.
So let's compromise.
I don't want to cause any
trouble for our parents.
Yeah. I honestly want them both to be happy.
If I know you're with other girls,
I might get jealous and anxious.
What do you think?
Same goes for me.
I wasn't... thrilled about the study session.
All right.
But you know, that kind of
jealousy isn't only between lovers.
I think it can happen between siblings, too.
So, Asamura-kun,
in front of anyone else,
we need to stay just brother and sister...
even if we're not really brother and sister.
Together, we can carry this weight...
as two special...
especially close...
I'm sorry. I can't.
I'm counting on you.
From now on, Ayase-san, I'll count on you.
So I want you to know you can count on me, too.
Let's... figure this out together.
Let's protect what we have
and figure this out...
together.
Thank you.
Yesterday, we were still only strangers.
And this is the story of how we became...
a true family.